const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Chylomicrons, intermediate-density lipoproteins (IDL), low-density lipoproteins (LDL), very-low-density lipoproteins (VLDL), and high-density lipoproteins (HDL) are all serum lipoproteins. Which of the following is the correct order of these particles from the lowest to the highest density?","answers":[{"option":"LDL, HDL, Chylomicrons, VLDL","bool":false},{"option":"IDL, VLDL, LDL, HDL","bool":false},{"option":"Chylomicrons, VLDL, IDL, LDL","bool":true},{"option":"VLDL, IDL, LDL, Chylomicrons","bool":false},{"option":"HDL, Chylomicrons, LDL, VLDL","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these is closely related to the partially hydrogenated oils?","answers":[{"option":"Saturated fats","bool":false},{"option":"Cis form of fat","bool":false},{"option":"Trans form of fat","bool":true},{"option":"Poly unsaturated fats","bool":false},{"option":"Mono unsaturated fats","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is a nonmodifiable risk factor for atherosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Cigarette smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperlipidemia","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following conditions can lead to concentric hypertrophy of the left ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Massive transfusion","bool":false},{"option":"Volume overload","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary atresia","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the normal cardiothoracic ratio on a posteroanterior (PA) radiograph of the chest in an adult?","answers":[{"option":"< 40%","bool":false},{"option":"< 30%","bool":false},{"option":"< 50%","bool":true},{"option":">60%","bool":false},{"option":">50%","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The ventricles are completely depolarized during which isoelectric portion of the electrocardiogram (ECG)?","answers":[{"option":"PR interval","bool":false},{"option":"ST segment","bool":true},{"option":"QRS complex","bool":false},{"option":"QT interval","bool":false},{"option":"T wave","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The common carotid artery and the first part of the internal carotid artery develop from which of the following aortic arches?","answers":[{"option":"First","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth","bool":false},{"option":"Second","bool":false},{"option":"Sixth","bool":false},{"option":"Third","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the odd statement regarding cardiovascular alterations in the tetralogy of Fallot?","answers":[{"option":"Interventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Overriding of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophy of the right ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 22-year-old woman comes to the clinic for a routine checkup. She has a short, webbed neck and short stature. Cytogenic analysis shows a karyotype of 45, XO. Which of the following heart defects is most likely to be present in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Right to left shunt","bool":false},{"option":"Left to right shunt","bool":false},{"option":"Patent foramen ovale","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 32-year-old man comes to the clinic with complaints of dyspnea, fatigue, exercise intolerance, and palpitations. On examination, he has a right ventricular heave, a holosystolic murmur, and a fixed, wide split S2. What is the most likely cause of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid atresia","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is most appropriate regarding congenital heart defects?","answers":[{"option":"Tricuspid atresia is associated with hypoplastic left ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis can lead to left ventricular hypertrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Severe pulmonary atresia leads to hypoplastic left ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Severe congenital aortic stenosis leads to hypoplasia of the right ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary atresia is associated with left ventricular endocardial fibroelastosis","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 55-year-old man has a significantly reduced concentration of bile salts in his blood. This is expected to lead to a significantly decreased absorption of which of the following substances?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Folic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Triacylglycerol","bool":true},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acids","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The blood of a person who has consumed large amounts of animal fat would most likely contain increased levels of which of the following lipid compounds?","answers":[{"option":"High-density lipoproteins","bool":false},{"option":"Phospholipids","bool":false},{"option":"Chylomicrons","bool":true},{"option":"Low-density lipoproteins","bool":false},{"option":"Very-low-density lipoproteins","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the basic biochemical defect in the membrane of low-density lipoprotein (LDL) molecules, that leads to the formation of atherosclerotic plaques?","answers":[{"option":"Disruption","bool":false},{"option":"Constitution","bool":false},{"option":"Less protein content","bool":false},{"option":"Peroxidation","bool":true},{"option":"Distorted shape","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following facilitates the uptake of cholesterol by high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) and its plasma esterification?","answers":[{"option":"Lipase:cholesterol acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoprotein:cholesterol acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Liposomal:cholesterol acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Lysosomal:cholesterol acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin:cholesterol acyltransferase","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"In the histological section of an elastic artery, the outer layer shows small vessels. To which of the following groups do these vessels belong?","answers":[{"option":"Venules","bool":false},{"option":"Lacteals","bool":false},{"option":"Vasa vasorum","bool":true},{"option":"Meta-arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Arterioles","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The histological section of the heart myocardium shows which of the following cell types?","answers":[{"option":"Stem cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje myocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardial endocrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac myocytes","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is inappropriate regarding the valves in the veins?","answers":[{"option":"Usually in paired structures","bool":false},{"option":"Able to prevent the backflow of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Lined with endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Formed from the folds of tunica intima","bool":false},{"option":"Inconspicuous in veins that transport blood against the force of gravity","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Crisis intervention is the immediate and short-term emergency response to mental, emotional, physical, and behavioral distress. The initial biopsychosocial assessment would require asking about suicidal thoughts and feelings, estimating the strength of the client's psychological intent to inflict deadly harm, gauging the lethality of the suicide plan, inquiring about suicide history, and taking into consideration certain risk factors. What is this stage known as?","answers":[{"option":"Solving the problem","bool":false},{"option":"Developing the action plan","bool":false},{"option":"Assessing safety and lethality","bool":true},{"option":"Addressing the feelings","bool":false},{"option":"Generating alternatives","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is a tertiary prevention approach for cardiovascular diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Providing prompt cardiovascular disease screening","bool":false},{"option":"Damage control and rehabilitation","bool":true},{"option":"Providing appropriate immunization facilities","bool":false},{"option":"Diagnosing the cases early","bool":false},{"option":"Identifying the high-risk cases","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following physiological changes in the cardiovascular system takes place during dynamic exercise but not during static exercise?","answers":[{"option":"Systolic blood pressure increases","bool":false},{"option":"Diastolic blood pressure increases","bool":false},{"option":"Heart rate increases","bool":false},{"option":"Diastolic blood pressure decreases","bool":true},{"option":"Cardiac output increases","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"During the cardiac cycle, the pressure rises and falls in the atria. One of the pressure waves is the 'c' wave. What does this wave indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Phase of slow ejection","bool":false},{"option":"Isovolumetric contraction","bool":true},{"option":"Phase of rapid filling","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of papillary muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Phase of rapid ejection","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the amount of blood present in ventricles during the isovolumetric relaxation phase called?","answers":[{"option":"Ejection fraction","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac index","bool":false},{"option":"End systolic volume","bool":true},{"option":"Stroke volume","bool":false},{"option":"End diastolic volume","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The long-term mechanism for the regulation of blood pressure involves regulating which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Vessel diameter","bool":false},{"option":"Stroke volume","bool":false},{"option":"Heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Blood volume","bool":true},{"option":"Contractility","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The second heart sound occurs at the start of which of the following phases of the cardiac cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Phase of rapid filling","bool":false},{"option":"Phase of atrial contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Phase of rapid ejection","bool":false},{"option":"Isovolumetric contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Isovolumetric relaxation","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following would increase due to increased vagal stimulation of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Q-T interval","bool":false},{"option":"QRS complex","bool":false},{"option":"S-T segment","bool":false},{"option":"P-R interval","bool":true},{"option":"T-P segment","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Epicardial coronary blood vessels have a preponderance of which of the following receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Muscarinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Beta adrenergic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha adrenergic receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Nicotinic receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The ability of tissues to regulate their own local blood flow permits them to maintain adequate nutrition and homeostasis from a given local blood flow in ml/min under basal conditions. Which of the following matches with that of the liver and the kidneys respectively?","answers":[{"option":"1050, 300","bool":false},{"option":"1350, 1100","bool":true},{"option":"25, 175","bool":false},{"option":"750, 250","bool":false},{"option":"700, 200","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following accurately reflects the blood flow to the kidney in ml/min/100 g of tissue weight under resting conditions?","answers":[{"option":"300","bool":false},{"option":"360","bool":true},{"option":"90","bool":false},{"option":"160","bool":false},{"option":"70","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The control of local blood flow to tissues depends on which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Antidiuretic hormone and aldosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Renin and angiotensin","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic response","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen demand and vasodilators","bool":true},{"option":"Level of carbon dioxide and membrane thickness","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 58-year-old man comes to the cardiac outpatient department with the complaint of chest pain that radiates to the back. A radiograph of the thorax reveals an aneurysm of the ascending aorta confirmed by a magnetic resonance angiogram. Which of the following is/are the branches of the affected part of the aorta?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic","bool":false},{"option":"Common carotid","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following nervous regulatory mechanisms of blood pressure mainly operates when arterial blood pressure falls to a very low level?","answers":[{"option":"Baroreceptor reflex","bool":false},{"option":"CNS ischemic response","bool":true},{"option":"Cushing reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system","bool":false},{"option":"Chemoreceptor reflex","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What part of the electrocardiogram (ECG) is represented by the Q-T segment?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial depolarization","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular repolarization","bool":false},{"option":"Both ventricular repolarization and depolarization","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular depolarization","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial reploarization","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which enzyme is released by kidneys in a hypovolemic, hypotensive, hyponatremic condition?","answers":[{"option":"Renin","bool":true},{"option":"Angiotensin I","bool":false},{"option":"Erythropoietin","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following gives rise to the right and left coronary arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic sinus of ascending aorta","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following type of vessels are present in liver, spleen and bone marrow?","answers":[{"option":"Continuous capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Sinusoidal capillaries","bool":true},{"option":"Elastic arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Fenestrated capillaries","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which cardiac layer is involved in right ventricular hypertrophy?","answers":[{"option":"Epicardium","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardium","bool":true},{"option":"Visceral layer of pericardium","bool":false},{"option":"Endocardium","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal layer of pericardium","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Heart belongs to which of the following mediastinum divisions?","answers":[{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Middle","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most sensitive early marker of myocardial Infarction?","answers":[{"option":"Myoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Aspartate aminotransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Creatine kinase MB","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac troponin I","bool":true},{"option":"Lactate dehydrogenase","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following forms the apex of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Right and left atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricle","bool":true},{"option":"Left atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Right and left ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"'a' wave in the atrial contraction curve represents which of the following events of the cardiac cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial contraction","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular emptying","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Isovolumetric ventricular contraction","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"'c' wave in the atrial contraction curve represents which of the following events of the cardiac cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular emptying","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular contraction","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular relaxation","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is true regarding isovolumetric contraction?","answers":[{"option":"Contraction of the ventricles and their emptying","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of the atria and their emptying","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of the ventricles without their emptying","bool":true},{"option":"Relaxation of the ventricles and their filling","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of the atria and filling of the ventricles","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following terms is used to describe the amount of blood pumped by the heart per minute?","answers":[{"option":"Ejection fraction","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac output","bool":true},{"option":"Stroke volume","bool":false},{"option":"End diastolic volume","bool":false},{"option":"End systolic volume","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following terms is used to describe the amount of blood ejected per beat?","answers":[{"option":"Stroke volume","bool":true},{"option":"Cardiac output","bool":false},{"option":"End diastolic volume","bool":false},{"option":"Ejection fraction","bool":false},{"option":"End systolic volume","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is at the highest risk of atherosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cigarette smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Consuming saturated fat diet","bool":true},{"option":"Compromised immune system","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is known as good cholesterol?","answers":[{"option":"Chylomicron","bool":false},{"option":"Low density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"High density lipoprotein","bool":true},{"option":"Intermediate density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Very low density lipoprotein","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following organisms causes endocarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"In bipolar limb leads if the positive electrode is attached to the left arm, which of the following leads is it labeled as?","answers":[{"option":"Lead aVF","bool":false},{"option":"Lead V1","bool":false},{"option":"Lead III","bool":false},{"option":"Lead II","bool":false},{"option":"Lead I","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which structure shifts blood from the pulmonary trunk to the aorta in fetal circulation?","answers":[{"option":"Fossa ovalis","bool":false},{"option":"Ductus arteriosus","bool":true},{"option":"Ductus venosus","bool":false},{"option":"Descending aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The positive terminal of the bipolar limb lead I is attached to which side of the body?","answers":[{"option":"Left arm","bool":true},{"option":"Right arm","bool":false},{"option":"Right leg","bool":false},{"option":"Left leg","bool":false},{"option":"Right hand","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Angina or ischemic heart pain can be silent in which of the following groups?","answers":[{"option":"Smokers","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertensive patients","bool":false},{"option":"Stressed people","bool":false},{"option":"Young people","bool":false},{"option":"Elderly people","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which one of the following is a common valvular disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral annular calcification","bool":false},{"option":"Calcific aortic stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Rheumatic heart disease","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid heart disease","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral valve prolapse","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"With which of the following conditions is dextrocardia distinctly recognized?","answers":[{"option":"Situs solitus","bool":false},{"option":"Situs ambiguous","bool":false},{"option":"Situs inversus","bool":true},{"option":"Transposition of great vessels","bool":false},{"option":"VACTREL complex","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Perforations in septum primum coalesce before the closure of foramen primum. This leads to the formation of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen secondum","bool":true},{"option":"Septum secundum","bool":false},{"option":"Sinus venosus","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"'v' wave in the atrial contraction curve represents which of the following events of the cardiac cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Beginning of ventricular contraction","bool":false},{"option":"End of atrial contraction","bool":false},{"option":"End of ventricular contraction","bool":true},{"option":"Ejection fraction","bool":false},{"option":"Stroke volume output","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A smooth part in the right atrium, which is a remnant of the right sinus horn is seen by some medical students while dissecting a cadaver. The part can be identified as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sinus venarum","bool":true},{"option":"Crista terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"Fossa ovalis","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the gold standard for diagnosing mitral valve stenosis?","answers":[{"option":"Electrocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Echocardiography","bool":true},{"option":"Troponin I test","bool":false},{"option":"Creatine kinase-MB test","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Plateau phase in cardiac muscles is caused by an influx of which ion?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium","bool":true},{"option":"Pottasium","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"During a plateau in cardiac muscles which of the following ions has decreased permeability?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Pottasium","bool":true},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following characterizes bradycardia?","answers":[{"option":"<60 beats per minute","bool":true},{"option":"<40 beats per minute","bool":false},{"option":">120 beats per minute","bool":false},{"option":"<70 beats per minute","bool":false},{"option":">100 beats per minute","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The rapid upstroke of the cardiac action potential is due to the opening of which of the following ion channels?","answers":[{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":true},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Where are ryanodine receptors present?","answers":[{"option":"Plasma membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi complex","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondria","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":true},{"option":"Sarcolemma","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"From which of the following aortic arches does ductus arteriosus arise?","answers":[{"option":"Left 4th aortic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Left 6th aortic arch","bool":true},{"option":"Right 6th aortic arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd aortic arch","bool":false},{"option":"1st aortic arch","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What are glycerol-containing phospholipids known as?","answers":[{"option":"Glycerophospholipid","bool":true},{"option":"Sphingolipid","bool":false},{"option":"Glycolipid","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosphingolipid","bool":false},{"option":"Phospholipid","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is a congenital heart defect with the right to left shunt?","answers":[{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Patent foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid atresia","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the angle of the unipolar lead aVF?","answers":[{"option":"+60 degrees","bool":false},{"option":"+90 degrees","bool":true},{"option":"Zero degree","bool":false},{"option":"-30 degrees","bool":false},{"option":"+120 degrees","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Lecithin cholesterol acyltransferase activity is associated with which of the following \r\nmolecules?","answers":[{"option":"Low density lipoprotein containing apolipoprotein B","bool":false},{"option":"High density lipoprotein containing apolipoprotein A1 and apolipoprotein A2","bool":false},{"option":"High density lipoprotein containing apolipoprotein A1","bool":true},{"option":"Very low density lipoprotein containing apolipoprotein B","bool":false},{"option":"High density lipoprotein containing apolipoprotein A2","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following types of phospholipids is present in high-density lipoproteins (HDL)?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphatidylserine","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphatidylinositol","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiolipin","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidylethanolamine","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which type of lipid is often present in atheromatous plaque?","answers":[{"option":"Membrane lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Low density lipoproteins","bool":false},{"option":"Phospholipids","bool":false},{"option":"Triglycerides","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesteryl esters","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following can help prevent cardiovascular diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Increased fiber intake","bool":false},{"option":"Exercise","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"Less saturated fat intake","bool":false},{"option":"Lifestyle modification","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Defect in which of the following cause(s) supraventricular tachycardia?","answers":[{"option":"Bundle of His","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje fibres","bool":false},{"option":"AV node","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Atria","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following lipids activates lecithin cholesterol acyltransferase (LCAT) in high-density lipoproteins (HDL)?","answers":[{"option":"Apolipoprotein A2","bool":false},{"option":"Apolipoprotein E","bool":false},{"option":"Apolipoprotein C","bool":false},{"option":"Apolipoprotein A1","bool":true},{"option":"Apolipoprotein B-48","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following biomarkers is cardiac specific?","answers":[{"option":"Creatine kinase-MB","bool":true},{"option":"Creatine kinase-MM","bool":false},{"option":"Lactate dehydrogenase-2","bool":false},{"option":"Lactate dehydrogenase-1","bool":false},{"option":"Lactate dehydrogenase-3","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Coarctation of the aorta is common in children. The aorta is classified as which type of artery?","answers":[{"option":"Medium elastic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Large elastic artery","bool":true},{"option":"Medium muscular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Large muscular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Small muscular artery","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following factors may directly cause turbulent blood flow?","answers":[{"option":"Increased flow","bool":false},{"option":"Increased diameter","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased velocity","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Partial occlusion of a blood vessel","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Lymphatic vessels are internally lined with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Collagen fibres","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic fibres","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Myocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Endocardium consists of which type of epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":true},{"option":"Simple columnar","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following events in the cardiac cycle produces the first heart sound?","answers":[{"option":"Closure of the aortic valve","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of the ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of the AV valves","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of the AV valves","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of atria","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following organisms causes prosthetic valve endocarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus viridans","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus mutans","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following receptors on the heart bring about the sympathetic effect?","answers":[{"option":"Gamma receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-1 adrenergic receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Beta-2 adrenergic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is a long-term condition developed by up to one-third of the population affected by the crisis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute stress disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Adaptive behaviour","bool":false},{"option":"Maladaptive behaviour","bool":false},{"option":"Post-traumatic stress disorder","bool":true},{"option":"Adjustment behaviour","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is considered a modifiable factor for coronary artery\r\ndisease?","answers":[{"option":"Genetic predisposition","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivity","bool":true},{"option":"Gender","bool":false},{"option":"Family history","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the correct anatomical position of the mitral valves?","answers":[{"option":"Fourth costal cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"Fourth intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Second intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Third costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Second costal cartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Sodium is a major constituent cation of which of the following compartments?","answers":[{"option":"Plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Extracellular fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Intracellular fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Blood","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The influx of which of the following ions causes a spike in the cardiac potential?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following ions is responsible for increased contraction strength of cardiac muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Pottasium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium ions","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride ions","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium ions","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Blood leaves the left ventricle through which of the following valves?","answers":[{"option":"Tricuspid valve","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral valve","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic valve","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary valve","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following types of vessels are lined with pericytes?","answers":[{"option":"Arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Veins","bool":false},{"option":"Capillaries","bool":true},{"option":"Venules","bool":false},{"option":"Arterioles","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding the fenestrated elastic membranes present in the elastic arteries?","answers":[{"option":"They will be different in males and females","bool":false},{"option":"They range in size from 60 nm to 70 nm","bool":false},{"option":"They will be different in different arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Their size range will increase will age","bool":true},{"option":"They will be different in different regions of body","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following does not open in the right atrium?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary veins","bool":true},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding the SA node?","answers":[{"option":"It is supplied by vagus nerve","bool":true},{"option":"It is located in both atria","bool":false},{"option":"It is supplied by the left coronary artery","bool":false},{"option":"It cannot generate impulse when completely denervated","bool":false},{"option":"It is joined to the AV node via purkinje fibres","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A patient presents to the outpatient department and is diagnosed with peripheral insufficiency due to decreased contractility of the heart. Which layer of the heart is responsible for contractility?","answers":[{"option":"Endocardium","bool":false},{"option":"Sub-epicardium","bool":false},{"option":"Epicardium","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardium","bool":true},{"option":"Pericardium","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is a rate-limiting enzyme in the beta-oxidation of fatty acids?","answers":[{"option":"Acetyl CoA carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG CoA reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin cholesterol acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Carnitine palmitoyltransferase I","bool":true}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following, on the electrocardiogram (ECG), represents the time between the beginning of electrical excitation of atria and the beginning of excitation of ventricles?","answers":[{"option":"QT interval","bool":false},{"option":"TP segment","bool":false},{"option":"PQ segment","bool":false},{"option":"ST segment","bool":false},{"option":"PR interval","bool":true}]}]
export default arr